are they and it is 11:00 a.m. so be here
to fix the world just clearly what's
happening your number let's just you
can't see that I have nothing on any of
my surfaces
I literally open up clean this up every
time is huge gotta see it full
disclosure it is October 11th which
means a month ago today I started the
first idea cafe on September 11th I've
done I did a bunch like four in a row on
the Wednesday at 11 a.m. and they were
amazing and great learning experiences
and this week was the first week I
changed it up completely I changed it so
instead of it being at 11 a.m. and I
picked the question and then trying to
find people which was feeling stressful
and too much for me I changed it so that
I'm finding one person we're designing a
question together and then we are
picking a time that works for both of us
and then whatever community that's
pertinent to we're splitting it up to
that community whether it's on Twitter
or Facebook or more niche communities
that I'm part of and this is the first
week of doing that and I had three
different idea cafes one on mental
health one on donor conception and one
on autism which were all amazing and I'm
loving the new format also this in two
days because that two days later on
after lunch the antia cafe I had this
for the first time and although that
wasn't necessarily life-changing right
before that I got introduced to game B
and I can't believe everything that has
occurred with game B in my life has
happened in the last month just seems
ridiculous having the conversations with
various people and then there's a big
conversation plan for this Tuesday I
haven't been as involved as I would like
to be on the Facebook group because I've
been doing my own game B which is maybe
not gave me but
figuring out what it means to me and
also like I've written writing it out
doesn't really work for me especially in
the format it's there every so often
I'll see a question that I want to
respond to it always ends up being a
week old I'm like oh no wonder having
that conversation I also am getting more
and more in touch with what my position
is in this and although I have the idea
that is game B that is how we can create
it starting today if people want to do
it which is creating a global tech
cooperative it gives us all of the
things that basically all of the
speakers talk about it helps people go
into flow it helps us work as both
sovereign individuals without having to
give without having to and looking after
each other like we get the group and the
individual and didn't there's like no
one here I did not put this it's like no
I don't think so
I don't think it's private maybe it is
it's what you can still be talking to
myself for a half an hour that should be
fun actually I think it was just the
awesome 59th uhm realizing that I had
this idea although it wasn't as good as
it is now two years ago and so I've had
to keep putting myself out there in a
way that is comfortable enough for me
that it doesn't feel like this huge leap
because I can't handle the stress of a
huge leap so I started out on periscope
I started out just kind of putting out
little things to my friends and family
that really didn't go anywhere and he
been on like I don't eat I can't even
I've had to do my own personal
development to get this thing going and
the personal developments I've done is
something that everyone can do in its
Omni win its non-rival risk which is
what a lot of I think the self-help
people that I follow and love are not
anti rival risk because they don't get
that beam wealthy is actually rival race
like having money means someone else has
less of it it's how money works it's not
I didn't invent it it's just how it
works and there's this thing in our
current game aim world's that people
with a certain ability with a certain
person
yet it's much easier for them some of
those people not all of those people at
some of those people who gained a works
for our sociopaths are narcissists the
more you're willing to screw over your
fellow man and be over competitive the
further you get and that doesn't mean
everyone who's successful does that but
the more you're willing to the more
you're willing the better you get and
the flip side of that is the more
compassionate you are the more you can
impact the more you care about your
fellow human being not only are you less
likely to be able to make money in this
game you it also comes with a real
health cost and so even the like piece
of the self-help community that is like
oh oh when you figure yourself out when
you do everything you need for you you
will get health and wealth and I'm like
neither of those things is guaranteed I
have been doing this work I've never
been happier I've never had more
capacity to deal with and at the
same time I'm neither healthy nor
wealthy partly because and I've watched
so many of the people who I know to be
caring compassionate individuals get
diagnosed with chronic illness get
chronic pain chronic fatigue chronic
anything cancer because that is part of
what the cost is to be in this planet
see the pain and not be able to do
anything on it game B doesn't require
gaming not to like it doesn't require
the people who are winning in game a to
stop being those people I don't think I
think game B has to tap into a space and
an advantage for every single human
being that doesn't mean we now make a
world that is completely antagonistic to
narcissists and sociopaths does they
exist they're part of our humanity but
we don't prop them up and put them make
them president/ceo we don't make them in
charge of the science and in charge of
our economics and politics and
everything we find places they find
places where they're able to contribute
in a
somewhat positive way I mean sometimes
the most positive thing you can do is be
the antagonist if that's your role
that's kind of trumps world moment and
so I'm realizing which I've known for
months that my role maybe isn't this
this thing this global cooperative
although I'm still gonna be here doing
fix the world Fridays I'm still gonna be
trying to figure out how to communicate
it but like the irony of being me like I
have this idea that I think is the
solution to the world yeah I can I mean
it's not something's one person can do
on their own but it is something that
someone who is more type-a and more
organized and less plus neurodiverse
more neurotypical could be could maybe
get off the ground much more easily but
that same brain wouldn't have come up
with it and so I can see that
definitely my challenges and the things
that society says make me less than or
actually what make it possible that I
was able to create this and I can see
how the diversity on this planet
especially the diversity that were less
okay with ie disability it mental
emotional physical are all key
components of how we work together as
humanity and so part of what I'm here to
do and I'm still figuring it out so I
don't necessarily know how to explain it
my world is that I'm here to do that
social or that personal development
piece but for the group instead of the
individual that it isn't about you
necessarily needing to meditate and eat
right and and you know we can find a way
to make more money it's about helping
each other do that like having this
piece of the world like when I'm
anti-capitalist and I am I'm
anti-capitalist I don't know how else to
explain it I don't think the solution is
ever to go backwards I don't think the
solution is to go back until we were all
tribal and there was no internet I don't
think the solution is to go and retry
communism in our countries I don't think
it's even to start unions and worker
cooperatives because those are old
technologies it has to be something new
it has to be something that gives us
more than what we currently have
ads individuals it has to be something
that entices us as individuals in our
own lives and it's like we went through
this really conformist part of our
history that was necessary to exist as a
cohesive group we needed to be cohesive
so therefore if you were the odd ball
you've got kicked out of the tribe you
got kicked out you were not a part of it
and there was a certain amount that that
was necessary and then we got to the
point where now we're completely
individualistic want more or less and
there was a positive and a negative that
came from that and I think the next step
forward is to have both of those things
to have you get to be a unique
individual you get to figure out who you
are and that path allowing people to
follow that path is how we do it all is
how we create the cooperative because
then you get people in flow then you get
people who are giving their best self
because that's what I've tapped into you
I'm like oh I still don't look very good
considering what society says we should
look like
I still can't work I still can't you
know I still can't run or do you know
cardio work I can't like I can't there's
a lot of things like our limitations for
me but the limitations I'm supposed to
have to live my life because they're my
roadmap and my way of getting there and
I can't be go tackle enough to think
that I'm unique and not that I'm somehow
better than or special that I have this
path and no one else does I think we all
have a path and it's not written in the
outside it's written in the inside and
we can't really judge each other's and
everyone following their own path in a
way that they're hopefully cognizant of
like what their decisions impact other
people I'm overly conscious of how my
decisions affect other people so I think
people that are maybe more sociopathic
and narcissistic need a little bit
figure out how to how to not be how to
you know incorporate other people's own
emotions and how their actions affect
the world and people like myself or
maybe more empathetic and overthink how
everything affects the world needs to be
a little more selfish
and that is what I've had to learn I've
had to learn how to put on my own gas
mask ear mask before helping other
people to the point where it's life or
death
I can't help the world unless I look
after myself first and I think I'm
having been the flipside but I'm sure
the flipside is true that you can't look
after yourself without looking after
other that's absolutely true
when you look at what cooperation gives
us on this planet even if you are only
in it for your best life there comes a
point where you're neighbors having
health care does better for you because
they're not passing on diseases to you
they're not stealing from you to pay for
their kids their insulin-like having a
system that works for everyone makes
your life better yet all of the
innovation it unlocks all of them which
you can't even know I know the
innovation I've unlocked in my head that
isn't reality yet but I can only imagine
what the innovation I hopefully can
create with other people it's going to
unlock for everyone else because that's
what it is it's the field we all play on
it's creating the tools that enable us
to live in flow to figure out and that's
the piece of life not the individual and
not the group it's be yourself and what
do you need what do you need to live
your better life what do you if you want
to eat healthy and you're not what's
stopping you and how can we co-create
that so you can eat healthier if you
want to be on time for things if you
want to learn something if you want what
is it you want and how can we co-create
it together that is the tools and
technology we are creating and so I'm
figuring how to keep it bad like I just
did which I think was fairly good
instead of and if we're gonna make
databases we all get spreadsheets um
which is not as exciting to other people
that's maybe that's me there's the big
piece of it is we allow people to geek
out where they want to get go and our
society is so focused on perfection that
we don't even know who we really are
because we're trying to be these perfect
copies into the world that that's what
all the self-help people tap into which
is powerful of like okay well listen to
your own inner guidance we'll get rich
and healthy from it no I have not gotten
rich and healthy but I think because
it's it's
health is something that's available to
everyone it's just not available to
everyone while we're destroying our
planet doesn't matter how healthy you
eat and how much clean water and
supplements you take on a planet that is
decaying on a planet where we're not
taking care of our mother we can only be
so healthy on planet where you're
stressed because your fellow humans are
hurting you can only be so healthy and
so when helping other people makes you
more healthy legitimately wealth is not
on me when wealth is the more you have
the less other people have power is the
more you have the less other people have
because what is power except power over
others empowerment having control on
your own life knowing who you are and
living in that is anti rival risks the
more you do it the more you give
permission for everyone else to do it
and the more we we are able to co-create
from that space and innovate and we have
all of the stuff that unlocks the more
we can tell have money because it's not
designed that way it's based on debt and
we can't even all be at zero what we can
do is all have abundance food is Omni
win creating new technology that helps
us create food without more pesticides
without more fertilizers but with
technology that is 3d farms and like of
indoor lighting like creating spaces or
when we figure out energy that's doable
right now Horsham relying on co2
emissions and other pollutants to create
our energy that is not a sustainable
option and we have sustainable energy
growing food indoors growing it
vertically growing it just figure you
know what works best for you and your
community and getting that information
though helps and then people start with
right it's like this greenhouse is the
best and then you innovate it to make it
even better and you make that technology
available to everyone people have that
if they're going to make that even
better and so innovating open source
innovating in a way that you know you're
allowed to improve it because nobody
owns it and we own it together and
that's what a global cooperation give us
and it's not we're the individuals
creating it so if I own that greenhouse
if it's my intellectual property
and I want to sell it to you that's fine
as long as it's open and transparent I'm
like okay and then someone else adds
something to it and they're like okay
well that who owns that well that's part
of the conversation and if you never
want anyone to touch it you never want
well then you're kind of playing game eh
and you're playing a tiny bit game B if
you're using our technology but okay as
long as that's transparent we are gonna
create a green house that's better than
yours because we are gonna open source
it and share it and so it's gonna
exponentially faster get better than
yours is even if it starts at a fraction
of the quality that yours does because
we're co-creating it together it's going
to get better faster and we're doing
things openly and transparently
and so I'm gonna wrap this up there's no
one here but I put this on private who
knows a last few ones for my other idea
Cafe have been on private and unlisted
so that might be what's happening um
having a space what I'm looking for it
cuz last Sunday I went for a walk
that's noodle season book club and he
was talking about tens and he's like
what's a ten for you I was like look at
you and go for a walk see yeah just left
him at broad and one of the realizations
I had although I'm enjoying this I'm
gonna continue doing this on Fridays I'm
like I don't want to talk to by myself
in a camera I like conversation and
that's what I'm doing on the idea Cafe
is showcasing a conversation creating a
platform for a conversation doing what
is fun and easy for me and having it
have hopefully an impact in the world
what I would love to do is find one
person just like the idea Cafe one
person who wants to meet weekly on
camera so the world can see and be our
little board meeting our little staff
meeting that is anything but that is
open as transparent is is vulnerable and
real about how we create a world that
works for everyone brings their ideas to
the table brings their insecurities
brings who they actually are and is
willing to have the tough conversations
and the fun easy conversations that get
us to yeah I have an idea doesn't have
to be my idea I can let go of my idea
I'm far enough along that I'm like right
have reasons for all of it I want to
bring those ideas to the table but we
can create a world that works for
everyone and that's about allowing
everyone to say what's a world that
works for you at no point do you get to
tell me how to create a world that works
for you I can offer a suggestion I can
offer advice I can ask I can ask you if
you need help and offer what I can give
but you don't get to give it up to the
government be like solve it for me I
want to pay no taxes and have you do
everything for me that's not a solution
nor can the corporation's be oh you want
to be no taxes and get all the benefit
we're not the government we're not a
corporation that is going to be designed
for profit we are a not-for-profit it's
going to co-create the solutions that we
need to live better lives
which means we're empowering the
individual with tools and a system and
just the wording come tell us what makes
your life hard and how do we make it
better what's our first project my first
projects the idea Cafe because it's the
one I can do I can do it for my capacity
someone else's first project might be a
food one might be something else might
be I don't I envision us doing one all
together and then moving on to the next
one I don't know what could have stopped
someone from creating the food up
especially if it's one we want to call
them together one they want to own but
they want to make it for Humanity this
isn't about it being my vision this is
about how do we create a world that
works for everyone
how do you enjoy creating it how do you
enjoy being what is gonna make you happy
that piece of it living your best life
is how you help the world when we're
happy when we're connected when we're
living our authentic lives we don't
consume yeah we might buy stuff yeah we
might not be perfect human beings we're
gonna make mistakes but we don't
consumer we don't like have the
addiction level that we currently have
as someone who experienced addiction is
living in addiction through addiction
through being an imperfect human being
that is what I've got me I'm not
supposed to perfect myself and perfect
this idea and then put it on a silver
platter for you here's how you get as
healthy and wealthy as me you too can do
it I'm supposed to showcase the journey
as raw
as vulnerable as I need to be to do that
that's the step I'm taking I'm getting
more vulnerable more real each time I
get the new insight like okay cool
that's what I need to do cool I don't
get it look cool that's neat
thanks universe but in OD about an Oni
that I get to be me like it's that weird
it's just weird and it's a fun game to
play as following your own internal map
there is no external reward they can't
offset that none no relationship no
finance no health it can give you what
following your own internal guy to give
you and my issue is I get that saying
that is not the same as living it and so
I'm like yeah basically sit on the couch
and get get six-pack ABS that's true you
can't you can't actually do those two
things but following your own internal
joy following your internal voice
including like meditations the best way
to get there and I still argue with
myself against meditation and I'm on
that journey but it's like the fastest
way but like that's a part of it and
then it's hard to sit down and listen to
your own internal thoughts is like well
that's not easy and simple right at this
moment and the more I own that and sit
with that the more I'm like I'll
meditation might be a nice thing to do
right now the more I put meditation the
more I naturally eat healthy instead of
what I used to do which is like how do
we figure this out and like throw
everything out that's bad and only cuz I
have like a juice cleanse basically
always fell apart on day two or three
and never really changed my life like it
seems to everybody else it's like how do
I add things that bring value and take
incremental steps in the right direction
the right direction for me the right
direction which is the right direction
for Humanity
I believe that everyone's is but that
might not be the case cuz some people
might be doing some weird but we
can't necessarily judge because there's
some stuff I've done that is definitely
at least grey and morality grey and
legality and yet it was who I needed to
be to get to where I am and I can only
and that's a piece of everyone else
someone has to be a drug dealer if
someone has to you know be a thief if
someone is it's like it's not about
helping them do that but understanding
that everyone's on their own journey and
asking people like why are you doing on
does that feel good for you in the
moment just that is that your highest
peace how do we help you get there
without demanding how they get there and
that is what we are gonna do for one or
defer to one another time so I can talk
to myself or half an hour um what we do
to get there is live our own lives at
that the highest point is were possibly
capable of at the moment which is
exactly what you're doing and that's the
thing is it's like there is no thing to
obtain outside of yourself you know
everything you need to know you are
everything you're supposed to be in this
moment right now and I don't yet know
how what I'm gonna show that I'm gonna
prove X I'm showcasing it myself
I'm already everything I'm supposed to
be I know everything I'm supposed to
know to create game be my piece of it my
piece of what I'm supposed to do and
that doesn't mean I don't grow and learn
I am growing and learning but it's like
I'm not learning in an outside source
someone's like you got to study this and
dig no I'm done I'm not doing that
that was university that was before
brain tumors when I was able to put an
external knowledge now I follow what I
want I listen to podcasts it like yeah
that's cool I read books that I can read
books again that intrigued me and are
fun to read how much of my health
journey and spiritual journey is like do
what you love it's like I can't read I
fall asleep unless you like it and it's
helps insomnia me go ahead all right I'm
gonna end this here this is how it was
clearly meant to be today
no one was here brother that was my
fault because maybe I put it on private
I don't know I'll put it on public after
if not Oh is there an edit button be
funny if I could edit it now or no it's
public it's public it's just that one
instant so I'm figuring out how to take
the next leap into like finding that one
person and part of the journey was
because I changed the world the idea
cafe this week on when
say I was free at 11 a.m. I'm like every
other week the last four and the world
cafe happens this week which is the
format that the idea Cafe is based on
and they have an online version that
they do monthly and I couldn't go to the
last month's but I went to the two
months previous this is the first time I
really got him experiencing because
there was enough participants that we
broke out into groups and there are
three people that I'm in contact with
and I'm like yes I have to email you and
figure out how to like have a
conversation whether it's me helping
them with their project then maybe
coming on board or just a conversation
like conversations are powerful and both
people if they're good conversations
leave a little bit different and that's
what I'm here to experience is those
situations those conversations those
like things that draw me in and we all
are there's nothing and my issue is that
I still am like but there's more you
have to be doing no there really isn't
all the rest of it it's just like keep
your house clean have fun with your kid
code nature be happy be happy it's the
best thing you can do for yourself and
the world and humanity by the world I
mean planet youth planet and humanity
it's the world is kind of blending
community and the animals a better world
is on its way if you watch this for 25
minutes please like and subscribe share
with your friends invite them let's
create a better world together
it isn't just possible it's probable
when enough of us get together enough of
us I mean to two of us get together we
showcase having fun doing it and then a
third person comes then a fourth person
and we get big enough we're going on
zooms so that 100 people can have a
conversation when that gets too big
we're doing other time we're probably
into other time zones I'm moving out
before time slots before we get to a
hundred people but creating we're gonna
figure it out as we go we're gonna make
mistakes together we're gonna correct
them we're gonna figure out what rum and
get them better and not the individual
like I'm not gonna make mistakes that
you get to tell me I get to fix I will
make mistakes and I will figure out what
I did wrong and I will fix them as I
meant to and together we will do the
group one with that and I'm still
figuring on how to do this process in a
group like know how to follow my own
inner guy but then it's like Oh Tia cafe
that's done we're doing it this way now
but that's because it wasn't working the
old way
so there's if it's working
people are coming on board it won't be
changing as rapidly as it is when it's
not yet working for my vision all right
I'm gonna go cuz I get to go for a
walkathon with my kid today it was
important to her and I normally go for a
walk out for this by myself in the
forest today instead I'm gonna go for a
walk like a bunch of elementary school
kids I'm bringing your plugs just in
case so take care and I will see you
next week and maybe earlier because I'm
gonna try to put out a couple videos a
week but I'm not quitting into that I am
open to that I'm open to the universe
giving me the message of like here's
what you need to do a video on and
actually doing it cuz it does do that
I'm gonna like no but know what I feel
like get dressed you know do it in your
pajamas I don't care do it in Veliz just
put yourself out there do what makes you
happy and just keeping steps forward and
the more you live your authentic light
the less you care about what society
things
yes society kind of gets I can't even
explain it all it's just magic do it
it's magic all right I was gonna hit the
chat button and said again broadcast
button bye YouTube